732-882-2308 · nick.bruce.anderson@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/nickbruceanderson · nickbruceanderson.github.io

Summary

A data enthusiast with 7 years' experience producing positive ROI at a Fortune 100 company for million-dollar initiatives.

Seeking a career shift to data science, where I can harness my knack for technical puzzle solving and storytelling. With proficiency in predictive modeling, analytics, and reporting, I can deliver actionable insights and business solutions.

Skills

Programming

- SQL, Excel, Python
- NumPy, Pandas, NLTK
- Sci-Kit Learn, TensorFlow

Data Analysis

- Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tableau
- A/B Testing, Segmentation
- Sentiment Analysis

Machine Learning

- Classification, Regression
- Clustering, NLP, Al
- Feature Engineering

Big Data & More

- Spark, Hadoop, AWS
- Statistics & Probability
- Github, Office Suite

Experience

Data Science Projects - UDEMY Bootcamp, Portfolio

Jan 2021 - Present

- Crafted NLP SMS-spam detection model achieving a 91% F-score (at 95% confidence) by implementing a custom text preprocessor, TF-IDF vectorization, and Naïve Bayes modeling on a UCI dataset of 5500 texts.
- Built an eCommerce regression to find a \$38/hour per consumer profit opportunity via train-test splits, elastic net, and cross validation to conclude user time on app leads to 38x more sales than time on website.
- Wrangled and cleansed terabytes of COVID-19 infection data using SQL to conduct field transformation, string parsing, standardization, duplicate removal, predictive null imputation, and succinct feature selection.
- Mathematic & applied ML competencies: linear & logistic regression, decision trees & random forests, support vector machines, K nearest neighbors, K means clustering, and principal component analysis.
- Distributed Systems and Big Data skills: HDFS, Map Reduce, using Spark & MLLib for model evaluation.
- Adept in statistical concepts: hypothesis testing, ANOVA, T-Test, Chi-Square, and Bayesian methodologies.

verizon o

Sr. Business Analyst – Verizon Global Risk Compliance Team

Jan 2016 - Mar 2019

- Netted \$5M in savings, leading 105 cross-departmental offshoring projects to approval & go-live operation.
- Designed self-serve Tableau dashboard that reduced 20,000 hours of manual reporting per year, enabling offshore KPIs via ETL design and collation of 50+ siloed data sources into a Hadoop data lake.

Business Analyst – Verizon Vendor Management Team

Aug 2014 – Jan 2016

- Enhanced project milestone forecasting by 33% through development of a Python app: Project Estimation Tool (PET). PET made timing predictions based on historical project milestone dates and features.
- Earned Six-Sigma award for process improvement, overhauling 20+ VISIO workflows to simplify workflows.

Project Manager – Verizon IT Finance PMO

Mar 2012 - Aug 2014

- Boosted ad-hoc project ROI reporting by 400% using Excel pivot tables, VBA, VLOOKUP & other formulas.
- Increased customer base by 2.6 million, managing AGILE projects for 20+ rural area telecom mergers.

J.P.Morgan \diamondsuit

Project Manager Intern – J.P. Morgan Fraud Analytics PMO

Jun 2011 - Aug 2011

Built custom UI, eliminating 2-week vendor development cycle, using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and PHP.

Knight

Project Manager Intern - Knight Capital Group Trade Platform PMO

Jun 2009 - Oct 2009

• Optimized 4 Bloomberg report processes by creating Python scripts, alleviating 8 hr/week of data entry.

Education



Stevens Institute of TechnologyBachelor of Computer Science

2012 Graduate